Brockton, Mass. Waldo Congregational Church records, 1896-1980.
Congregational Library Archives
Brockton, Mass. Waldo Congregational Church records, 1896-1980.
RG5396
Congregational Library Archives
0.7 Cubic Feet
(2 boxes)
The Waldo Congregational Church was gathered in 1896 two years after being founded as the Montello Mission. In 1980 the Waldo Congregational Church, First Parish Congregational Church, South Congregational Church, and Porter Congregational Church merged to form the Christ Congregational Church. This collection contains the administrative and membership records of the church and includes record books, financial records, and vital member records.
Waldo Congregational Church (Brockton, Mass.)
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Materials were donated to the Congregational Library & Archives by the Waldo Congregational Church in 1980. Materials were sepparated out of RG0037 in March, 2019; Accession 2019-05.
Historical Note
The Waldo Congregational Church in Brockton was started in 1894 as the Montello Mission. The Montello Mission was administered by the Church Work Committee of the Porter Evangelical Church until 1896 when the mission was officially gathered as the Waldo Congregational Church. The parish met in the north of Brockton at the corner of North Main Street and Willow Street. In 1980 the Waldo Congregational Church, First Parish Congregational Church, South Congregational Church, and Porter Congregational Church merged to form the Christ Congregational Church. The old church building no longer exists.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the administrative and membership records of the Waldo Congregational Church in Brockton, Massachusetts. The collection includes church record books, member registries, financial records, annual reports, special orders of worship, and the financial records of the church's Sunday school.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged, primarily, in chronological order, and, secondarily, by topic.
Related Materials
In 1980, the First Parish Congregational, South Congregational, Porter Congregational, and Waldo Congregational Churchs merged into a single entity, the Christ Congregational Church. The records of all four churches are held at the Congregational Library & Archives:
Brockton, Mass. First Parish Congregational Church records, 1738-1980.
Brockton, Mass. South Congregational Church, 1835-1979.
Brockton, Mass. Porter Congregational Church, 1800-1979.
Baptismal records.; Church finance.; Church membership.; Church records and registers.; Sunday schools.; Brockton (Mass.) -- Church history.; Waldo Congregational Church (Brockton, Mass.)
- Church records, 1896 1923; 1896-1923 (Box 1, Volume 1)
- Church records, 1923 1980; 1923-1980 (Box 1, Volume 2)
- Church register, 1896 1931; 1896-1931 (Box 1, Volume 3)
- Church register, 1932 1980; 1932-1980 (Box 1, Volume 4)
- Treasurer's book, 1896 1912; 1896-1912 (Box 2, Volume 1)
- By-laws, 1896 1960; 1896-1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Church history, 1917 (Box 2, Volume 2)
- Rededication services, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Annual reports, 1928 1931; 1928-1931 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Annual reports, 1932 1935; 1932-1935 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Annual reports, 1936 1939; 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Annual reports, 1940 1944; 1940-1944 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Annual reports, 1945 1950; 1945-1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Waldo Church School account book, 1947 1958; 1947-1958 (Box 2, Volume 3)